[
    {
        "question": "What is the most RAM (in GB) on a 32-bit system?", 
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "True or false: a 64-bit system can handle more than 1,000 GB of RAM.", 
        "answer": true
    },
    {
        "question": "The core files that makes up an Operating System, outside of programs and device drivers, are called the... what?", 
        "answer": "kernel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the four main sections of the Operating Systems market?", 
        "answer": "Business Client, Network Operating System, Home Client, Mobile Operating System"
    },
    {
        "question": "Say an impending windows update is labeled the Spring Stoners Update (2004).  What is the Month and Year of the update, in the format 'June 1973'?", 
        "answer": "April 2020"
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: Windows 10 Home cannot join a domain.", 
        "answer": true
    },
    {
        "question": "Fill in: Windows tool to encrypt all information on a disk drive. Not present in Home.", 
        "answer": "BitLocker"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fill in: Windows tool to apply file or folder level encryption. Not present in Home.", 
        "answer": "Encrypting File System (EFS)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fill in: Windows tool to synchronize cached versions of shared folders and assets to reduce WAN traffic. Not present in Home.", 
        "answer": "BranchCache"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long are standard versions of Windows supported?", 
        "answer": "5 years standard updates, an extra 5 years of extended upport, meaning just security updates."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the end of service schedule for Windows10 Feature Updates?", 
        "answer": "18 months, but Education and Enterprise get 30 months for September updates."
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the iOS and MacOS End of Life policies?", 
        "answer": "There are no official End of Life policies."
    },
    {
        "question": "True or false: The full path to an object (including any file name and extension) may not usually exceed 100 characters.", 
        "answer": "false: standard limit is 260 characters"
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: MBR style Partitioning Scheme is limited to 4 Primary Partitions.", 
        "answer": true
    },
    {
        "question": "How big is a single sector (the smallest unit of storage on a fixed disk, traditionally)?", 
        "answer": "512 bytes"
    },
    {
        "question": "The New Technology File System (NTFS) is a proprietary file system developed exclusively for use with which operating system?", 
        "answer": "Windows. Obviously."
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: Libraries have been hidden by default on every version of Windows since 7.",
        "answer": true
    },
    {
	    "question": "True or False: The prompt 'C:\\Windows\\System32' will be displayed if accessing the command prompt as an administrator.",
	    "answer": true
    },
    {
	    "question": "What is the native Windows Command Prompt command to list files and directories?",
	    "answer": "DIR"
    },
	{
		"question": "How much RAM does Windows 10 (64 bit) need?",
		"answer": "> 2 GB"
	},
	{
		"question": "How much HDD space does Windows 10 (x64) need?",
		"answer": "20 GB free space"
	},
	{
		"question": "What's the shittiest processor you can use with Windows 10 (x64)?",
		"answer": "1 GHz CPU with support for PAE, NX, and SSE2"
	},
	{
		"question": "How much RAM does Windows 10 (x86) need?",
		"answer": "> 1 GB"
	},
	{
		"question": "How much HDD space does Windows 10 (x86) need?",
		"answer": "16 GB free space"
	},
	{
		"question": "What's the shittiest processor you can use with Windows 10 (x86)?",
		"answer": "1 GHz CPU with support for PAE, NX, and SSE2"
	},
	{
		"question": "How much RAM does Windows 8/8.1 (64 bit) need?",
		"answer": "> 2 GB"
	},
	{
		"question": "How much HDD space does Windows 8/8.1 (x64) need?",
		"answer": "20 GB free space"
	},
	{
		"question": "What's the shittiest processor you can use with Windows 8/8.1 (x64)?",
		"answer": "1 GHz CPU with support for PAE, NX, and SSE2"
	},
	{
		"question": "How much RAM does Windows 8/8.1 (x86) need?",
		"answer": "> 1 GB"
	},
	{
		"question": "How much HDD space does Windows 8/8.1 (x86) need?",
		"answer": "16 GB free space"
	},
	{
		"question": "What's the shittiest processor you can use with Windows 8/8.1 (x86)?",
		"answer": "1 GHz CPU with support for PAE, NX, and SSE2"
	},
	{
		"question": "How much RAM does Windows 7 (x86) need?",
		"answer": "> 1 GB"
	},
	{
		"question": "How much HDD space does Windows 7 (x86) need?",
		"answer": "16 GB free space"
	},
	{
		"question": "What's the shittiest processor you can use with Windows 7 (x86)?",
		"answer": "1 GHz CPU"
	},
	{
		"question": "How much RAM does Windows 7 (x64) need?",
		"answer": "> 2 GB"
	},
	{
		"question": "How much HDD space does Windows 7 (x64) need?",
		"answer": "20 GB free space"
	},
	{
		"question": "What's the shittiest processor you can use with Windows 7 (x64)?",
		"answer": "1 GHz CPU"
	},
	{
		"question": "True or False: the memory management feature for the x86 architecutre allowing CPUs to access more than 4GB of ram is called Physical Address Extension, or PAE",
		"answer": true
	},
	{
		"question": "How does the NX bit work?",
		"answer": "This bit is used to mark certain areas of memory as non-executable. The processor will then refuse to execute any code in these areas.  Primary application is preventing takeover from malicious software."
	},
	{
		"question": "True or False: Processors that support PAE, NX, and SSE2 are required for every version of Windows AFTER 7",
		"answer": true
	},
	{
        "question": "True or False: 64 bit shared files are in the system32 folder of a 64 bit system, while 32 bit are stored in the syswow64 folder.",
        "answer": true
    },
    {
        "question": "Policies, including automatic program installation, can be set for a group of computers on a domain using what?",
        "answer": "GPOs, or Group Policy Objects"
    },
    {
        "question": "Windows Universal Apps are different than traditional programs in what ways?",
        "answer": "They run in a restrictive sandbox preventing system wide changes, meaning a standard account can install."
    },
    {
        "question": "A Windows process that does not require any sort of user interaction, and thus runs in the background, is called a what?",
        "answer": "a service"
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: Print Management as an administrative tool is available in all versions of Windows 10.",
        "answer": "false, not available in home additions."
    },
    {
        "question": "A means for developers to link software applications and leverage windows services is called the, what? \n An example is embedding an excel table into word.",
        "answer": "Compontent Object Model."
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: Enabeling remote assistance on a windows computer requires enabeling Remote Desktop.",
        "answer": "False - Remote Assistance requires consent at connection, remote desktop opens up to connections anytime."
    },
    {
        "question": "Counter logs saved from the Performance Monitor do what?",
        "answer": "Collect statistics about resources that can determine system health and performance."
    },
    {
        "question": "Trace logs saved from the Performance Monitor do what?",
        "answer": "Collect statistics about services, providing detailed reports about resource behavior.  Think of as an extension to the Event Viewer."
    }	
]
